<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://nho1ix.github.io/persephone/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://nho1ix.github.io/persephone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-12-15T12:34:50+00:00</updated><id>https://nho1ix.github.io/persephone/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Shichi</title><subtitle>Vic's Blog</subtitle><entry><title type="html">An update</title><link href="https://nho1ix.github.io/persephone/2022/09/13/update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An update" /><published>2022-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nho1ix.github.io/persephone/2022/09/13/update</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nho1ix.github.io/persephone/2022/09/13/update.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/6008e7c64dfdb80938cd0cf9/1612335007114-BTBOK8XUS1J26488I175/hiatus_wordmark-01.png&quot; alt=&quot;On Hiatus&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been about 9 months since my last post. To be honest, I had plans to use this blog more frequently, but laziness crept over me, and I ended up not using it at all. Depending on how it goes, either I might seriously start using this blog again, which I’ve never really started, but hey, never too late to start 😝, or just stop using it again for a long period of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, I wanted to talk about the more important parts of what I was planning to do recently. I’ve already told my mom a couple days ago that I wasn’t going to college. Albeit sad news, I do have a plan:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get a job&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Study coding while on the job&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Envision a [best-case/worst-case] scenario for my life&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hopefully settle down in a year’s time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get my driver’s license&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maybe reconnect with friends more&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Re-start doing dual n-back&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think with how things are going, it’s not very certain if this will be the way I’m conducting my plans, but it’s better than nothing for now. Most of my plans tend to really just be on the spot spontaneous plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think what I can start doing, is starting to create deadlines for when I should complete The Odin Project course. With big milestones broken down into smaller weekly and daily chunks, it should be a good visual way to see how much progress I am making. I could also use these blog formatted posts to keep track of the knowledge I’ve gathered, as well as any other thoughts I come up with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the novel things about journaling is the actual physical contact with the pen and paper that I just don’t get with typing into a blog, ironically. I wish I was able to journal or write faster and neater, or just memorize things better I guess. Maybe I should also look into restarting dual n-back (let me put this as #7 on the list). My memory is conventionally terrible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, it’s time to wrap up this post. Hopefully, I’ll continue to update it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My personal questions</title><link href="https://nho1ix.github.io/persephone/2022/01/20/my-personal-questions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My personal questions" /><published>2022-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nho1ix.github.io/persephone/2022/01/20/my-personal-questions</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nho1ix.github.io/persephone/2022/01/20/my-personal-questions.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://crystal.cafe/b/src/1624324312871.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://crystal.cafe/b/src/1624324312871.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Life of Crime&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that its the new year, I wanted to make an update to the last post, about my feelings of urgency to do something about the future. College is obviously not in my future, as now that the deadline for colleges and universities have passed, I have essentially closed the door that leads towards college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the two week winter break that we had, I had an extremely depressive period, where I was on my bed with my phone sideways all day. I would get up to do the basic necessities, such as brushing my teeth, showering, eating food, but after that, I would jump straight back into bed like a slob. One thing I would say that helped me get through that depressive period faster than I thought however was to just literally “feel” through the time. Instead of distracting myself with shitty memes or video games or any vice, I just laid there with my shitty feelings. After the two week period however, I noticed a change. I’d say this change really helped me sort my life together and start making the changes to my life that future me would be happy about. I began to care less about things I’d usually worry about. Things that would feel nervous to me like presenting now was as easy as talking to a teacher. It honestly felt like I was flowing down with the River of Life, instead of against it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made this blog post to list out the things that I have on my mind about what I want to think about or do in the future. Maybe they will help someone in a similar situation as I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are my plans after high school?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Whether to use the money I amassed across my 4 years of high school to buy a car or to save it and use it for something else?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creating a timetable for my day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Treating my memory issues&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Figuring out how to retain the knowledge gained after reading books&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Is college for you?</title><link href="https://nho1ix.github.io/persephone/2021/09/21/is-college-for-you.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is college for you?" /><published>2021-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nho1ix.github.io/persephone/2021/09/21/is-college-for-you</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nho1ix.github.io/persephone/2021/09/21/is-college-for-you.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://commondatastorage.googleapis.com/ctnetimages%2FReasonsToReturnToCollegeWordCloud650.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://commondatastorage.googleapis.com/ctnetimages%2FReasonsToReturnToCollegeWordCloud650.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;College&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting closer to 18, I’ve felt the increasing urgency to start thinking about what I’m going to do in the future. I’ve had the same thoughts as others, “How about college?” My conclusion? &lt;strong&gt;It’s not worth it anymore&lt;/strong&gt;. I’ve found that too many people go to college more for the experience rather than what they’re really learning. Paying for college classes only to go party every weekend is quite a waste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let’s say you’re not the type to party every week, and you’re very studious and academic oriented. Some good questions to ask yourself to see if you’re on the right track are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are you taking college courses that have &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; to do with your major?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Taking geology, chemistry, fine arts, and Spanish to satisfy requirements for an &lt;strong&gt;IT degree&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A business major taking women’s studies, sociology, gender studies, etc&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you have a scholarship to the college or university you’re planning to attend?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is college helping you make connections that you can contact in the future?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are you majoring in something that is not in high demand or does not provide any job market value in the real world?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Communications&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Gender studies&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Art history&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Music&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Religious studies&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can you work the jobs you want right after high school without going to college (this question excludes those who wish to go into specialized professions such as the medical (doctor, nurse) / legal (lawyer, etc) / STEM fields)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have you done research on whether you can really pay off the college debt you rack up? Or have you taken the words of others saying that you could easily pay it off once you graduate for granted?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Could it be better to have &lt;em&gt;zero debt&lt;/em&gt; and a &lt;em&gt;lower income&lt;/em&gt; compared to a &lt;em&gt;high debt load and higher income?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of these questions are targeted about really thinking deeper about the things that people never think about when they want to go to college. For example, if you and Person A are applying to a job at a company, and you have had no interactions with the company before, but Person A is friends with the president of the company, who do you think will get the spot?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1280/3557/articles/Connection_Blog_Big.jpg?v=1562700128&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1280/3557/articles/Connection_Blog_Big.jpg?v=1562700128&quot; alt=&quot;Connections&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Connections are one of the biggest unspoken trump cards that people never seem to bring up. Making and having connections that can get you into places, whether it be McDonald’s or Google, is a valuable skill and card to possess. I’m not saying that you have to do it, but it gives you more options to explore, similar to how an affluent family has many options in regards to spending and choosing due ot the amount of money that they possess, compared to a more impoverished family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are studies from educational websites &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brookings.edu/blog/up-front/2020/10/08/major-decisions-what-graduates-earn-over-their-lifetimes/#cancel&quot;&gt;such as this one&lt;/a&gt; that state:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“At the median, career earnings for a bachelor’s degree graduate are more than twice as high as for someone with only a high school diploma or GED, roughly 70 percent higher than for someone with some college but no degree, and more than 45 percent higher than for someone with an associate degree.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, this seems great on paper, but doesn’t take into account that most college graduates are likey already conscientious and intelligent, and would do just fine even if they don’t go to college. This study doesn’t account for the college debt that you acquire. According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/05/16/opinion/college-useful-cost-jobs.html&quot;&gt;New York Times&lt;/a&gt;, they state:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“But for those born into poverty, the results were far less impressive. College graduates born poor earned on average only slightly more than did high school graduates born middle class. And over time, even this small “degree bonus” ebbed away, at least for men: By middle age, male college graduates raised in poverty were earning less than non-degree holders born into the middle class. The scholars conclude, “Individuals from poorer backgrounds may be encountering a glass ceiling that even a bachelor’s degree does not break.””&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now what, “woe is me?” No. There are many options out there if you do your research, but it’s important that you try to focus on getting a skill or trade or anything that you get paid for, and that the world needs.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to my blog.</title><link href="https://nho1ix.github.io/persephone/2021/09/19/welcome.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to my blog." /><published>2021-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nho1ix.github.io/persephone/2021/09/19/welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nho1ix.github.io/persephone/2021/09/19/welcome.html">&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.incimages.com/uploaded_files/image/1920x1080/getty_625390400_200013341818843182339_374947.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past couple of years, I wished that there was a place that I could store my notes as well as thoughts in a format that is able to be consumed by many. I found that there wasn’t really an outlet for me to publish my ideas or thoughts as well as a website. I felt that social media should be kept for posting about professional work. I personally prefer to not post about memes or random things on Instagram, as I feel that it is a waste of time for myself and those viewing my page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-process-of-making-my-blog&quot;&gt;The process of making my blog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought that hosting a website and posting on there would be a good idea, only to actually do it for about a month or 2, and I found that the overhead cost was too much for me. It costed about $4.50 a month to host my website, which generally is pretty cheap, but to me was expenseive since nobody really ever visits my website anyway, so it would be a waste of money. Eventually, I ended up finding out that I could host websites for free with Github Pages, provided I have the files for the layout of the page.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>